Guide to the World Student Christian Federation Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- G: Australasia, Series LVI
  - G500 Organized Lines of Work and Study. Religious Departments and Meetings.
    - G550 Social study and service. Community welfare work, religious and philanthropic, outside of student body. Home missions
      - G554 Social service. Obligations as to community service implied in Christianity and resting upon the Church
        - G554.1 Enlistment of voluntary service
          - ASCM social service registration form (Box 246, Folder 2034)
    - G560 Entertainment. Athletics. Hygiene
      - Burton. Fun, 1922 (Box 246, Folder 2035)
    - G570 Business and publicity. Appeals for financial aid
      - Leaflets re. finances (Box 246, Folder 2035)
  - G600 Associations in Individual Institutions or among Special Classes of Students
    - G610 Colleges, universities and student departments of metropolitan and state associations
      - General
        - G610.1 Bibliography, general library catalogues
          - Melbourne University Christian Union Library Catalogue, 1900 (Box 246, Folder 2036)
        - G610.3 Service cards and blanks
          - Otago University Christian Union membership application (Box 246, Folder 2036)
      - G611 Objects and field
        - Article re. ASCU, 1906 (Box 246, Folder 2036)
      - G613 Organization, incorporation
        - G613.1 Constitution and membership
          - St. John's College Christian Union constitution (Box 246, Folder 2037)
          - Sydney University Christian Union constitution, 1896 (Box 246, Folder 2037)
      - G615 Organized lines of work and study
        - G615.004 Term programs
          - Syllabus cards for various Chris-tian unions (Box 246, Folder 2037)
        - G615.1 Evangelistic and philanthropic work among students
          - G615.14 Work for schoolboys and schoolgirls
            - G615.141 Camps
              - University Women's Camp for School Girls (Box 246, Folder 2037)
        - G615.2 Devotional and inspirational
          - Canterbury College Christian Union - suggested topics for prayer (Box 246, Folder 2037)
        - G615.8 Handbook of university information for new students
          - Various university handbooks published by the respective Christian unions, ca.1900 (Box 246, Folder 2038)
      - G619 History
        - G619.1 Reports
          - General
            - Melbourne University Christian Alliance, 1889-1890 (Box 246, Folder 2039)
          - G619.12 General committee minutes and documents
            - Adelaide University Christian Union Presidential reports, 1900-1906 (Box 246, Folder 2039)
            - Canterbury College Christian Union Presidential report, 1903-1904 (Box 246, Folder 2039)
            - Article re. Otago College Christian Union, 1903 (Box 246, Folder 2040)
        - G619.6 Conferences and conventions
          - G619.69 Student discussion conferences
            - Te Aute College Students' Association conference reports, 1902-1903 (Box 246, Folder 2040)
  - G700 Student Life in General Outside the Federation
    - General
      - New South Wales Scripture Union report, 1904-1906 (Box 246, Folder 2041)
    - G702 University catalogues, educational bulletins
      - Thwing. Higher Education in Australia and New Zealand, 1922 (Box 246, Folder 2041)
      - Dallen. The University of Sydney: Its History and Progress, 1925 (Box 246, Folder 2041)
    - G790 History
      - G791 Reports
        - Christchurch YMCA, 1912-1913 (Box 247, Folder 2042)
      - G795 Periodicals
        - Hermes, University of Sydney magazine (Box 247, Folder 2043)
  - G800 Correspondence
    - ASCM correspondence, 1918-1922 (Box 304, Folder 2829)
  - G900 History
    - General
      - ASCU constitutions, 1909-1915 (Box 247, Folder 2044)
      - ASCU reports, minutes, pamphlets, etc., 1903-1915 (Box 247, Folder 2045)
      - Letter from Mott to Fries re. W. Temple's visit to Australia, 1910 (Box 247, Folder 2046)
      - Letters/materials re. Rouse's visit to Australia, 1908 (Box 247, Folder 2047)
    - G910 Reports
      - General
        - First annual report of the ASCU, 1897 (Box 247, Folder 2048)
        - ASCM reports, 1924-1927 (Box 247, Folder 2048)
        - ASCM reports, 1918, n.d. (Box 304, Folder 2830)
      - G911 Reports of progress
        - ASCU, 1908,1917-1919 (Box 247, Folder 2049)
        - ASCM, 1926 (Box 247, Folder 2049)
      - G911.1 Directories
        - ASCU (Box 247, Folder 2049)
      - G912 General Committee Minutes and Documents
        - General committee reports, 1901-1904 (Box 247, Folder 2050)
        - General committee reports, 1911-1917 (Box 247, Folder 2051)
        - ASCU General report, 1921 (Box 247, Folder 2052)
      - G912K Secretaries Reports and Memoranda
        - General Secretary report, 1912 (Box 247, Folder 2052)
    - G920 Biography in general
      - Article re. W.H. Sallmon, 1898 (Box 247, Folder 2053)
    - G960 Conventions and conferences, educational and legislative
      - G961 Plenary conferences
        - Summer conference materials, 1899-1927 (Box 247, Folder 2054)
      - G967 Sundry conferences
        - Letters, articles re. various conferences (Box 247, Folder 2055)
        - Press notices re. summer conference at Sydney, 1898 (Box 247, Folder 2056)
        - Press notices re. summer conference at Nelson, 1899 (Box 247, Folder 2057)
      - G968 Leaders' Conferences
        - ASCU/ASCM conference programs, 1900-1927 (Box 248, Folder 2058)
      - G969 Student Discussion Conferences
        - Reports/Addresses of ASCU conferences, 1910-1912 (Box 248, Folder 2059)
        - Press notice re. Melbourne Student Convention, 1896 (Box 248, Folder 2059)
        - Business convention at Littagong reports, 1926 (Box 248, Folder 2060)
- G(a): Australia, Series LVII
  - G(a)300 Organization, Incorporation
    - G(a)310 Constitution and membership
      - ASCM constitution, 1922 (Box 248, Folder 2061)
  - G(a)500 Organized Lines of Work and Study. Religious Departments and Meetings. General Methods
    - G(a)510 Evangelistic and philanthropic work among students
      - G(a)512 Personal work texts
        - Jamieson. The Meaning of Life, 1928 (Box 248, Folder 2061)
        - Lade, et al. Faith, 1927 (Box 248, Folder 2061)
        - Mott. The Race Problem, 1926 (Box 248, Folder 2061)
        - Wyllie. Religion in Action, 1928 (Box 248, Folder 2061)
        - Haslem. The Hero of Men: A Study of Jesus for Use in Secondary Schools, 1929 (Box 304, Folder 2831)
    - G(a)520 Devotional and inspirational
      - G(a)522 Days and weeks of prayer
        - G(a)522.1 Calls to prayer
          - WSCF Universal Day of Prayer, 1922 (Box 248, Folder 2061)
    - G(a)530 Bible Study
      - G(a)532 Text-books
        - Garnsey. God's Purpose for Human Life, 1940 (Box 304, Folder 2832)
    - G(a)550 Social study and service. Community welfare work, religious and philanthropic, outside of student body. Home missions
      - G(a)555 Institutions and organizations for social effort on behalf of students
        - European Student Relief materials (Box 248, Folder 2061)
  - G(a)800 Correspondence
    - G(a)801 John Mott w/
      - Stanley Addison, 1910-1920 (Box 248, Folder 2062)
      - Henry Barraclough, 1897-1910 (Box 248, Folder 2063)
      - Margaret Holmes, 1917-1938 (Box 248, Folder 2064-2065)
    - G(a)810 Ruth Rouse w/
      - Stanley Addison, 1908-1909 (Box 248, Folder 2066)
      - Hilda Alexander, 1914-1915 (Box 248, Folder 2067)
      - Henry Aschdale, 1915-1916 (Box 248, Folder 2068)
      - Florence Holden, 1908-1910 (Box 248, Folder 2069)
      - Margaret Holmes, 1917,1918, 1923 (Box 249, Folder 2070)
      - Ida Slack, 1908-1922 (Box 249, Folder 2071)
      - Australian women student leaders, 1905-1914 (Box 249, Folder 2072)
  - G(a)900 History
    - General
      - Brochure for ASCU Annual Meeting, 1923 (Box 249, Folder 2074)
    - G(a)910 Reports
      - Budget reports, general (Box 249, Folder 2074)
    - G(a)911 Reports of progress
      - General committee report, 1923 (Box 249, Folder 2075)
      - ASCU general report, 1921 (Box 249, Folder 2075)
    - G(a)912 General Committee Minutes and Documents
      - E.F. Crosthwait's report re. Australia, 1917 (Box 249, Folder 2076)
    - G(a)960 Conventions and conferences, educational and legislative
      - General
        - Paper re. WSCF and international relations (Box 249, Folder 2076)
        - Leaflets re. ASCM summer conference, 1924 (Box 249, Folder 2077)
      - G(a)967 Sundry Conferences
        - Barton. Impressions of Christchurch conference, 1903 (Box 249, Folder 2077)
        - Letters from Barton and Bertram to Mott, 1896 (Box 249, Folder 2077)
- G(b) New Zealand, Series LVIII
  - G(b)100 Objects and Field, Extension and Supervision
    - G(b)120 Relationships and polity
      - G(b)123 International
        - Pamphlet re NZSCM in relation to WSCF (Box 249, Folder 2078)
  - G(b)300 Organization, Incorporation
    - G(b)310 Constitution and Membership
      - Various NZSCM constitutions and drafts, 1920-1921, n.d. (Box 249, Folder 2078)
      - Extracts from the Constitution of the NZSCM, 1921 (Box 304, Folder 2833)
  - G(b)500 Organized Lines of Work and Study. Religious Departments and Meetings.
    - G(b)520 Devotional and inspirational
      - G(b)522 Days and weeks of prayer
        - G(b)522.1 Calls to prayer
          - Day of Prayer leaflets, 1921-1922 (Box 249, Folder 2079)
        - G(b)522.2 Prayer cycles, litanies and daily helps
          - Intercession prayer leaflets, 1921-1927 (Box 249, Folder 2080)
    - G(b)530 Bible study
      - G(b)532 Text-books
        - Studies in the Life of Jesus (Box 249, Folder 2080)
      - G(b)533 Outlines from texts
        - Christian Missions and International Brotherhood (Box 249, Folder 2080)
    - G(b)550 Social study and service. Community welfare work, religious and philanthropic, outside of student body. Home missions
      - G(b)555 Institutions and Organizations for Social Effort on behalf of students
        - Materials re. European Student Relief, 1920,1927, n.d. (Box 249, Folder 2081)
        - Article re. Russian students in exile, 1926 (Box 249, Folder 2082)
    - G(b)570 Business and publicity. Appeals for financial aid
      - Our Movement, Finance Week (Box 249, Folder 2082)
  - G(b)800 Correspondence
    - G(b)801 John Mott w/
      - Donald Grant, 1926-1932 (Box 249, Folder 2083)
      - Margaret Walker, 1903-1906 (Box 249, Folder 2084)
    - G(b)810 Ruth Rouse w/
      - Jessie Abernathy, 1910-1913 (Box 249, Folder 2085)
      - Jean Begg, 1908 (Box 249, Folder 2086)
      - Constance Grant, 1920-1921 (Box 249, Folder 2087)
      - Elsie Griffin, 1908-1910 (Box 249, Folder 2088)
      - Margaret Walker, 1912-1923 (Box 249, Folder 2089)
      - Women students and leaders, 1905-1910 (Box 249, Folder 2090)
  - G(b)900 History
    - General
      - Materials re. New Zealand Cooperating Committee, 1917-1919 (Box 249, Folder 2091)
      - Historical documents re. NZSCM after its separation from ASCM (Box 249, Folder 2092)
    - G(b)910 Reports
      - Various NZSCM reports, 1917-1921 (Box 249, Folder 2093)
      - Various NZSCM reports, 1924-1926 (Box 304, Folder 2834)
    - G(b)912 General Committee Minutes and Documents
      - Many reports, 1918-1926 (Box 250, Folder 2094-2097)
    - G(b)950 Periodicals
      - Open Windows (Box 250, Folder 2098)
    - G(b)960 Conventions and conferences, educational and legislative
      - G(b)968 Leaders' Conferences
        - Program for Solway conference, 1923 (Box 250, Folder 2099)
- H South Africa, Series LIX
  - H000 General
    - H011 Publishers' prospectuses, trade lists, announcements
      - SCA literature, 1911 (Box 250, Folder 2100)
    - H030 Service cards and blanks, including questionnaires, record and subscription blanks and membership cards
      - Membership cards (Box 250, Folder 2100)
  - H100 Objects and Field, Extension and Supervision
    - Pamphlets re. SCA (Box 250, Folder 2101)
    - Hanleiding Voor de Christelijke Studenten Vereeniging (Box 250, Folder 2101)
  - H300 Organization, Incorporation
    - H310 Constitution and Membership
      - Various SCA constitutions, proposed and completed, 1907,1912, 1919, n.d. (Box 250, Folder 2102)
  - H500 ORGANIZED LINES OF WORK AND STUDY. RELIGIOUS DEPARTMENTS AND MEETINGS. GENERAL METHODS
    - H510 Evangelistic and philanthropic work among students
      - H512 Personal work texts
        - Merwe. Christus en de Ledendaagse twijfel (Box 251, Folder 2103)
        - Merwe. De Christen, De Drank en het Drankmisbruick, 1912 (Box 251, Folder 2103)
        - Trumbull. Een Overwinnend Leven, 1920 (Box 251, Folder 2103)
        - Malan. Waar is Abel, uw Broeder?, 1910 (Box 251, Folder 2103)
        - Malan. Een Pleit voor Onkunde en Haat, 1908 (Box 251, Folder 2103)
        - Hely-Hutchinson. Citizenship, 1909 (Box 251, Folder 2103)
      - H514 Work for schoolboys and schoolgirls
        - Program for SCA children's meetings, 1897 (Box 251, Folder 2104)
      - H515 Deputation work among the colleges
        - Reports/articles re. Donald Fraser's work among the colleges, 1896-1897 (Box 251, Folder 2104)
    - H520 Devotional and inspirational. The Morning Watch
      - General
        - Jannasch. Onze Kerkmuziek (Box 251, Folder 2105)
        - Mott. Intercessors: The Primary Need (Box 251, Folder 2105)
        - de Villiers. Het Onze Vader (Box 251, Folder 2105)
        - Eene Beweging in het Geestelijk Leven (Box 251, Folder 2105)
      - H522 Days and weeks of prayer
        - H522.1 Calls to prayer
          - Various calls, 1905,1909 (Box 251, Folder 2106)
        - H522.2 Prayer cycles, litanies and daily helps
          - Prayer cycles (Box 251, Folder 2106)
        - H522.3 Song books, religious poetry
          - Various hymn sheets, 1906, n.d. (Box 251, Folder 2107)
    - H530 Bible study
      - General
        - Hints on Bible study, 1912 (Box 251, Folder 2108)
        - De Bijbel en de Kerk, 1918 (Box 251, Folder 2108)
      - H532 Text-books
        - Items in card catalog and other leaflets (Box 252, Folder 2109)
    - H540 Mission study and service. SVM. YWCA. Foreign departments
      - General
        - The SVM of South Africa, 1916 (Box 253, Folder 2110)
      - H542 Text-books
        - Het Kruis in de Stille Zuied Zee, 1916 (Box 253, Folder 2110)
      - H544 Mission service
        - General
          - Gerdener. De Wereld en het Woord, 1908 (Box 253, Folder 2111)
        - H544.3 Claims of Christianity over other religions. Comparative religion. Apologetics
          - Wood. Een Stroom en een Banier (Box 253, Folder 2111)
        - H544.4 Need of support at home in men, money and prayer, and works toward these ends
          - Wat Nieuws (Box 253, Folder 2111)
        - H544.41 Prayer cycles for mission work
          - South Africa Missions prayer cycles, 1912-1913 (Box 253, Folder 2111)
      - H545 Enlistment for life work in missions
        - H545.2 Need for specialists
          - Murray. De Opvoeding in de Zending der Nedard. Geref. Kerk, 1913 (Box 253, Folder 2112)
      - H549 History of the student missionary movement as distinguished from the SCM as a whole
        - H549.2 Biography of missionaries
          - Jan Hofmeyr, 1914 (Box 253, Folder 2112)
          - Uitgave. De Kleine Jan van Kongwe, 1916 (Box 253, Folder 2112)
          - Jan Hofmeyer, 1915 (Box 253, Folder 2112)
        - H549.5 Periodicals
          - Mission News Letter, 1895-1896 (Box 253, Folder 2113)
        - H549.6 Conferences
          - H549.61 Plenary conferences
            - SCA Student's Missionary Conference at Somerset, 1908 (Box 253, Folder 2114)
          - H549.68 Leaders' Conference
            - Program for Blantyre conference, 1904 (Box 253, Folder 2114)
    - H550 Social study and service. Community welfare work, religious and philanthropic, outside of student body
      - General
        - Gerdener. Sosiale Studies, 1920 (Box 253, Folder 2115)
      - H556 Social morality
        - Gerdener. Hoeder of Broeder?, 1920 (Box 253, Folder 2115)
      - H556.2 Sex education
        - Bisseker. Voor Jonges alleen, 1914 (Box 253, Folder 2115)
        - Snowdrops: A Talk to Girls (Box 253, Folder 2115)
    - H560 Entertainment. Athletics. Hygiene
      - Kinder-Kransen, 1913 (Box 253, Folder 2116)
    - H570 Business and publicity
      - Various leaflets re finances (Box 253, Folder 2116)
  - H600 Associations in Individual Institutions or among Special Classes of Students
    - H610 Colleges, universities and student departments of metropolitan and state associations
      - H610.69
        - Die Christendom en Sociale Reconstruksie, 1923 (Box 253, Folder 2117)
      - H613 Organization, incorporation
        - H613.1 Constitution and membership
          - Various SCA constitutions (Box 253, Folder 2117)
      - H615 Organized lines of work and study
        - H615.004 Terms programs
          - Syllabus of meetings for Lovedale Missionary Institutions, 1898 (Box 253, Folder 2118)
      - H619 History
        - H619.111 Directories
          - Lovedale SCA, 1897 (Box 253, Folder 2118)
  - H700 Student Life in General Outside the Federation
    - General
      - Materials re. The Huguenot College of South Africa (Box 253, Folder 2118)
    - H750 Organized lines of work and study
      - H754 Mission study and service
        - Low. A Visit to Lovedale, 1897 (Box 253, Folder 2118)
      - H755 Social study and service
        - H755.6 Social morality
          - South African League of Purity handbook (Box 253, Folder 2118)
  - H800 Correspondence
    - H801 John Mott w/
      - Oswin B. Bull, 1906-1925 (Box 253, Folder 2119-2120)
      - Donald Fraser, 1897 (Box 253, Folder 2121)
      - G.B.A. Gerdener, 1906-1923 (Box 254, Folder 2122-2123)
      - Marguerite Kriel, 1913-1925 (Box 254, Folder 2124)
      - F.J. Liebenberg, 1933-1937 (Box 254, Folder 2125)
    - H810 Ruth Rouse w/
      - Oswin Bull, 1907-1919 (Box 254, Folder 2126)
      - Marguerite Kriel, 1912-1918 (Box 254, Folder 2127)
      - Women students and leaders, 1906,1920 (Box 254, Folder 2128)
  - H900 History
    - General
      - Letters important to the history of the South African SCA, 1896-1906 (Box 254, Folder 2129)
      - Historical documents, 1906-1924 (Box 254, Folder 2130)
      - The Students' Christian Association of South Africa. After 21 Years: 1896-1917 (Box 304, Folder 2835)
    - H910 Reports
      - General
        - Executive and general reports, 1915-1921 (Box 254, Folder 2131)
      - H912 General Committee Minutes and Documents
        - Agenda of Dutch Reformed Interracial conference (Box 254, Folder 2131)
      - H912E Secretaries' Reports and Memoranda
        - Henry L. Henriod's reports re. visit to South Africa, 1923 (Box 254, Folder 2132)
    - H920 Biography in general
      - Uitgave. De Kleine Jan Van Kongwe, 1922 (Box 254, Folder 2133)
      - Lyall. Constance Drummond: A Girl Disciple, 1904 (Box 254, Folder 2133)
    - H950 Periodicals
      - The Christian Teacher, 1913-1917 (Box 254, Folder 2134)
      - The SCA News Letter, 1923 (Box 254, Folder 2135)
    - H960 Conventions and conferences, educational and legislative
      - H960.16 Reports
        - SCA conference at Cape Town, 1906 (Box 255, Folder 2136)
      - H961 Plenary Conferences
        - Information circulars re. SCA meetings, 1896-1899 (Box 255, Folder 2137)
      - H967 Sundry Conferences
        - Conference hymnals, 1902,1903, 1923 (Box 255, Folder 2137)
        - SCA conference at Stellenbosch, 1896 (Box 255, Folder 2138)
        - Bantu-European Conference - Fort Hare College, Alice, Cape Province, 1930 (Box 304, Folder 2836)
      - H968 Leaders' Conferences
        - Programs for SCA conferences, 1899,1916-1919 (Box 255, Folder 2138)
      - H969 Student Discussion Conferences
        - Notes, addresses, etc., 1904,1916 (Box 255, Folder 2138)
- K: Malaya Netherlands East Indies (Indonesia), Series LX
  - K500 Organized Lines of Work and Study. Religious Departments and Meetings. General Methods
    - K540 Mission study and service. Student Volunteer Movement. Foreign Departments
      - K549 History of the student missionary movement as distinguished from the Student Christian Movement as a whole
        - K549.5 Periodicals
          - The Pioneer, 1938 (Box 304, Folder 2838)
- M: Lands Without National Organizations, Series LXI
  - General
    - Notebook of Thornton B. Penfield re. Lands without National Organization, 1902-1905 (Box 255, Folder 2139)
  - M800 Correspondence
    - M801 John Mott w/
      - Thornton Penfield (see also: F(i)801), 1905-1906 (Box 255, Folder 2140)
    - M810 Ruth Rouse w/
      - Robert P. Wilder, 1921-1924 (Box 255, Folder 2141)
    - M830 Thornton Penfield w/ (see also: F(i)801)
      - Raymond P. Dougherty, 1907 (Box 255, Folder 2142)
      - Lewis B. Hillis, 1905-1906 (Box 255, Folder 2143)
      - E.C. Jenkins, 1904 (Box 255, Folder 2144)
  - M900 History
    - General
      - Report of Thornton Penfield re. Egypt, 1905 (Box 255, Folder 2145)
    - M910 Reports
      - General
        - Work of the Federation in Lands without National Organization, 1919 (Box 304, Folder 2839)
      - M911 Reports of progress
        - M911.1 Directories
          - Various student societies in Lands without National Organization, 1909 (Box 255, Folder 2146)
      - M912 General Committee Minutes and Documents
        - Wilder. Special Study re. WSCF in Lands without National Organization, 1926 (Box 255, Folder 2147)
        - Wilder Ewald. Report of the Movement in Lands without National Organization, 1920-1921 (Box 304, Folder 2840)
    - M950 Periodicals
      - Occasional News Letter of the SCM re. Lands without National Organization, 1902-1906 (Box 255, Folder 2148)
    - M990 Miscellaneous Historical Documents
      - Mott's personal notes re. Lands without National Organization, ca.1901 (Box 255, Folder 2140)